<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-26T17:30:23+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Thinh’s Jekyll Blog</title><subtitle>This Jekyll Blog is an output of doing demo for reporting the subject's results for teacher Anh.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Report: Iran Hackers Targeted US Officials, Nuclear Experts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/24/ReportIranHackersTargetedUSOfficialsNuclearExperts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Report: Iran Hackers Targeted US Officials, Nuclear Experts" /><published>2018-12-24T15:32:30+07:00</published><updated>2018-12-24T15:32:30+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/24/ReportIranHackersTargetedUSOfficialsNuclearExperts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/24/ReportIranHackersTargetedUSOfficialsNuclearExperts.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/FA271753-2D34-4AEF-8D36-23B2CF48CB37_w1023_r1_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Report: Iran Hackers Targeted US Officials, Nuclear Experts Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image - Certfa researchers Nariman Gharib (L) and Amin Sabeti look at a computer at a cafe in London on Dec. 7, 2018.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://learningenglish.voanews.com/embed/player/0/4699599.html?type=audio&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;144&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iranian government-supported hackers have reportedly tried to break into the personal emails of American officials and international nuclear experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Associated Press, or AP, reported on the attempted attacks Thursday. The AP’s report was based on information collected during an investigation by the internet security company Certfa, which is based in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AP said the group, known as Charming Kitten, is believed to have tried to break into the private emails of more than 12 U.S. Treasury officials. The attempts took place over the past month. Other targets included well-known defenders, opponents and enforcers of an international nuclear deal signed in 2015 with Iran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the hackers sought to break into the emails of some Arab nuclear scientists and Iranian civil society members. Employees of major American research groups, known as think tanks, were also targeted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One target was Frederick Kagan, who works for the American Enterprise Institute, a think tank based in Washington. Kagan has repeatedly written about Iranian cyberespionage efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Presumably, some of this is about figuring out what is going on with sanctions,” Kagan told the AP. He was speaking about economic sanctions the U.S. has placed on Iran. The latest sanctions, on Iran’s oil and financial industry, were announced last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those restrictions officially cut off trade ties the U.S. permitted Iran after a nuclear agreement was completed in 2015. The U.S., Britain, China, France, Russia and Germany signed that agreement, along with Iran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/C3393C3F-B282-4569-A19F-AB1F01758D06_w650_r1_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Report: Iran Hackers Targeted US Officials, Nuclear Experts Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image - In this June 25, 2018 file photo, a group of protesters chant slogans at the old grand bazaar in Tehran, Iran.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. President Donald Trump announced last May that the U.S. would withdraw from the agreement. Trump said the deal permitted Iran to continue secretly developing nuclear weapons and provided it money to support violence across the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kagan said he was concerned about the latest reported hacking attempts. “This is a little more worrisome than I would have expected,” he said. He added that the information in Certfa’s report had all the signs of a state-supported operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certfa said its investigation found the hackers used Virtual Private Networks, or VPNs, to make it look like they were operating from France and the Netherlands. But the group said it uncovered strong evidence to prove that the hackers were operating from inside Iran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certfa researcher Nariman Gharib said it is not clear how many personal emails the hackers were able to successfully break into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iran has previously denied responsibility for hacking operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charming Kitten’s targets suggest that they are of interest to Iran’s government. One was a scientist working on a civilian nuclear project for Pakistan’s Ministry of Defense. Another worked as an operator at the Research and Training Reactor in the Jordanian city of Ramtha. A third was a high-ranking researcher at the Atomic Energy Commission of Syria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AP said the three targeted individuals suggested a general interest in nuclear technology and administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Bryan Lynn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bryan Lynn wrote this story for VOA Learning English, based on reports from the Associated Press and Certfa. Mario Ritter Jr. was the editor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Image - Certfa researchers Nariman Gharib (L) and Amin Sabeti look at a computer at a cafe in London on Dec. 7, 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">More and More People Want to Migrate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/24/More-and-More-People-Want-to-Migrate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="More and More People Want to Migrate" /><published>2018-12-24T15:32:30+07:00</published><updated>2018-12-24T15:32:30+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/24/More%20and%20More%20People%20Want%20to%20Migrate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/24/More-and-More-People-Want-to-Migrate.html">&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://learningenglish.voanews.com/embed/player/0/4711229.html?type=audio&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;144&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent study found that more than 750 million people would move permanently to another country if they had the chance. In other words, 15 percent of the world’s population wants to migrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallup company carried out the study. Researchers spoke to close to 500,000 people in 152 countries. They found that the desire to migrate rose between 2015 and 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the reasons people want to move from their home countries remain the same, said Gallup official Jon Clifton. They want to flee a crisis, or they are seeking better economic opportunities. Starvation and disaster also continue to drive people from their homes, Gallup found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do people want to leave?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the top 10 countries people want to leave is Syria. Gallup researchers found that at least 50 percent of Syrians want to migrate permanently and leave the war there behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People in several places in Latin America are also showing growing desires to migrate, Gallup found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gallup official Jon Clifton gave Venezuela as an example. Even though the country is rich in oil, it has fallen into a crisis, Clifton said. The United Nations estimates that around 2 million Venezuelans left their country in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desire to leave for another country also increased in a number of areas known for sending migrants. These include sub-Saharan Africa, the Caribbean, the Middle East and North Africa. One reason is that parts of Africa have had to deal with a spread of the deadly Ebola virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Europe, people in Albania had the highest rates of wanting to leave. Gallup reports that 60 percent of Albanians want to migrate. Clifton said many Albanians were unhappy about the amount of money they could earn, and how little it could buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other Balkan countries also showed high rates of migration desires. Clifton said the trend there was especially troubling, because it affected the youngest and most educated part of the population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separately, Gallup noted that in all regions of Asia “the percentage of adults who would like to move to another country permanently has remained flat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do people want to go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallup survey found that people who want to migrate hope to go to wealthy countries that observe the rule of law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gallup has been doing the survey for the last 13 years, Clifton said. During that time, the United States has always been the first choice for people who want to migrate. This year is no different, he said, even though U.S. President Donald Trump has taken measures and spoken out against migrants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People still see that this is one of the best economic opportunities for them in the world,” Clifton said of the United States. Many people around the world also have family members in the country already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallup survey found that one in five possible migrants said the United States would be their first choice for a new home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey also found that one in six Americans would like to migrate somewhere else – the highest number so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Kelly Jean Kelly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ardita Dunellari from VOA News. Kelly Jean Kelly adapted it for Learning English. Ashley Thompson was the editor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">US Allies Worry about Mattis’ Resignation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/21/USAlliesWorryaboutMattis-Resignation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="US Allies Worry about Mattis’ Resignation" /><published>2018-12-21T15:32:30+07:00</published><updated>2018-12-21T15:32:30+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/21/USAlliesWorryaboutMattis%E2%80%99Resignation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/21/USAlliesWorryaboutMattis-Resignation.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/6AABBFA2-052F-43AF-B359-FA40D5F0790A_cx0_cy6_cw0_w1023_r1_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;US Allies Worry about Mattis’ Resignation Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image - President Trump gets a briefing from his senior military leaders, including Defense Secretary James Mattis (L), in the Cabinet Room at the White House, October 23, 2018.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://learningenglish.voanews.com/embed/player/0/4711330.html?type=audio&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;144&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pop-out player
Traditional allies of the United States are expressing concern about the resignation of U.S. Defense Secretary Jim Mattis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump announced Thursday that Mattis will leave the job in February. The announcement came a day after Trump said that U.S. troops would leave Syria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Defense Department opposed the troop withdrawal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For several years, U.S.-supported forces in the Middle East have made progress against the Islamic State (IS). Defeating IS forces was just one part of a plan Mattis had for Syria. He wanted to reduce U.S. troop numbers there after successful completion of the three-part plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The president and Mattis disagreed on the issue. They also have different ideas about support for America’s traditional alliances. In his resignation letter, Mattis wrote that the United States cannot protect its interests without “showing respect to (our) allies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overseas reaction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The French Defense Minister Florence Parly spoke about the resignation. She said that French forces were in Middle East as part of a coalition “led by the Americans.” Trump’s decision “changes the situation,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Britain’s Minister of State for the Middle East, Alistair Burt, wrote that “If allies cannot be relied upon, others are sought to take their place.” The social networking website Twitter published his comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Former Swedish Prime Minister Carl Bildt tweeted the U.S. move was a “morning of alarm in Europe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defense Secretary Mattis is one of the most highly respected members of Trump’s foreign policy team. He helped lead the invasion of Iraq in 2003 and later led the U.S. Central Command until he retired in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his resignation letter to Trump, Mattis wrote that the president should have a Secretary of Defense who agreed with him on foreign policy. He added, “I believe it is right for me to step down from my position.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to Syria, the two men disagreed about other issues, such the president’s decision pull the United States out of the nuclear deal with Iran. They also have differences of opinion about Russian President Vladimir Putin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trump has praised Putin’s leadership skills. Mattis believed the Russian president was interfering with Western democracies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russia has praised the U.S. decision to withdraw from Syria. In a separate move, Trump ordered the Defense Department to plan to withdraw about 50 percent of the 14,000 U.S. troops in Afghanistan. That withdrawal will reportedly begin in January 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. congressional reaction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reacting to Mattis’ resignation, Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell said he was “distressed” that it resulted from “differences (about) America’s global leadership.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi said she was “shaken” by the resignation and described it as “very serious for our country.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is scary,” tweeted Senator Mark Warner of Virginia. He is the top Democrat on the Senate Intelligence Committee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trump’s decision to leave Syria breaks with one of America’s longtime allies, the Kurds. Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan has threatened in recent days to launch a military operation against U.S.-aided Kurdish militiamen now fighting in northeastern Syria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Susan Shand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Susan Shand adapted this story for Learning English based on reports from VOA News, the Associated Press and Reuters. George Grow was the editor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Image - President Trump gets a briefing from his senior military leaders, including Defense Secretary James Mattis (L), in the Cabinet Room at the White House, October 23, 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reaction to Trump’s Decision to Withdraw US Forces from Syria</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/20/ReactiontoTrump-sDecisiontoWithdrawUSForcesfromSyria.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reaction to Trump’s Decision to Withdraw US Forces from Syria" /><published>2018-12-20T15:32:30+07:00</published><updated>2018-12-20T15:32:30+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/20/ReactiontoTrump%E2%80%99sDecisiontoWithdrawUSForcesfromSyria</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/20/ReactiontoTrump-sDecisiontoWithdrawUSForcesfromSyria.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/F1230F78-5CC1-4A33-BC28-1EC59D9DF270_cx0_cy7_cw0_w1023_r1_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reaction to Trump’s Decision to Withdraw US Forces from Syria&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://learningenglish.voanews.com/embed/player/0/4709654.html?type=audio&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;144&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Syrian Kurdish allies of the United States are worried about President Donald Trump’s decision to withdraw all U.S. military forces from Syria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kurdish Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF) said in a statement Thursday that a U.S. withdrawal could give Islamic State (IS) militants a chance to regroup. It noted that Turkey has threatened to launch an offensive against Kurdish forces east of the Euphrates River.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trump announced the unexpected withdrawal – first in a statement and later in a video message – on Twitter Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We have won against (IS), we’ve beaten them and we’ve beaten them badly,” he said, adding “now it’s time for our troops to come back home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After historic victories against ISIS, it’s time to bring our great young people home! pic.twitter.com/xoNjFzQFTp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) December 19, 2018
U.S. lawmakers reacted with surprise to the president’s decision to immediately begin withdrawing all U.S. troops in Syria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rhode Island Senator Jack Reed told reporters the Trump administration is abandoning the Kurds to a “bloody conflict with Turkey.” Reed, a member of the Democratic Party, called the decision a “betrayal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Carolina Senator Lindsey Graham said the decision was a “disaster in the making.” Graham belongs to the Republican Party and is usually a Trump supporter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;France and Britain expressed concern about the U.S. announcement. The two countries are important members of the 60-member, anti-IS alliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A British government statement released Wednesday noted that “much remains to be done and we must not lose sight of the threat…(IS) remains a threat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;France’s European Affairs minister said that “the fight against terrorism is not over.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Moscow, Russian President Vladimir Putin welcomed the U.S. decision. At his yearly press conference on Thursday, Putin said he agreed with Trump. He added that the United States “has done the right thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The administration and the U.S. Defense Department have yet to explain how the nearly 2,000 American soldiers in Syria would be safely removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defense Secretary James Mattis and other U.S officials have been calling for American troops to stay in Syria to completely destroy Islamic State forces. The group still controls a few small areas of Syrian territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/DBD2D062-AA25-4194-A6FD-1D3917422A78_w650_r0_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reaction to Trump’s Decision to Withdraw US Forces from Syria&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;   &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;FILE - U.S. soldiers surveil the area during a combined joint patrol in Manbij, Syria, Nov. 1, 2018.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan said he had won “concessions” during a long telephone call with Trump. Erdogan said they talked about a Turkish offensive against the Kurds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Middle East experts have strongly criticized the president’s decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charles Lister at Washington’s Middle East Institute called the move a “dream scenario” for IS, Russia, Iran and Syrian President Bashar al-Assad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard Haas is president of the Council on Foreign Relations. He said it is “morally wrong” to leave the Syrian Kurds to face Turkey alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Syrian civil war began in 2011. It has left nearly 500,000 dead and millions homeless. In 2014, Islamic State militants seized control of several parts of Syria. While IS forces are mostly destroyed, they still hold territory in northeastern Syria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Jonathan Evans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Susan Shand adapted this VOA News report for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vietnam to Increase Electricity Production with Natural Gas Imports</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/vietnam/news/2018/12/19/Vietnam-to-Increase-Electricity-Production-with-Natural-Gas-Imports.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vietnam to Increase Electricity Production with Natural Gas Imports" /><published>2018-12-19T10:55:46+07:00</published><updated>2018-12-19T10:55:46+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/vietnam/news/2018/12/19/Vietnam%20to%20Increase%20Electricity%20Production%20with%20Natural%20Gas%20Imports</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/vietnam/news/2018/12/19/Vietnam-to-Increase-Electricity-Production-with-Natural-Gas-Imports.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/6D47230E-CA8C-4BAF-9EEF-FEBDEC452721_cx5_cy0_cw92_w1023_r1_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vietnam to Increase Electricity Production with Natural Gas Imports Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image - Liquefied natural gas can be transported by ship and needs infrastructure to be used as a fuel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://learningenglish.voanews.com/embed/player/0/4708015.html?type=audio&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;144&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam plans to start using liquefied natural gas, or LNG, by the year 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Vietnam has said it would be hurt by the effects of climate change, it plans to move forward with plans to import LNG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision shows how difficult it is to balance energy costs with efforts to protect the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le Van Luc is with Vietnam’s Ministry of Industry and Trade. He said that as the economy grows, energy supplies have not kept up with demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that, for many years, his country was an energy exporter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“However, in 2015, we became a net energy importer, especially of coal and natural gas,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Climate change concerns compete with energy needs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam is home to nearly 100 million people. It was among the nations that sent representatives to the recent climate change talks in Katowice, Poland. The United Nations gathering failed to set targets for the reduction of carbon gases linked to rising temperatures in Earth’s atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Southeast Asian countries, such as Indonesia and Thailand, plan to burn more coal to meet their energy needs, yet they fear the effects of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam is turning to imports of liquefied natural gas partly because policymakers believe there are limits to renewable energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luc notes that the country is reaching the upper limit of electricity production from dams. Wind and solar power are more costly than LNG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United States wants Vietnam to use LNG because U.S. companies could export it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, the U.S. government organized a conference on natural gas. At the event, the U.S. consul general in Ho Chi Minh City, Mary Tarnowka, warned of energy shortages in southern Vietnam. She said that the city has economic growth of 10 percent, but energy is needed to fuel that growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All of this is creating a growing middle class, and a society and culture that is growing as quickly as their energy demands,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tarnowka added that demand for energy is growing at nearly eight percent this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural gas has traditionally been transported through pipelines. But for longer distances, it can be cooled into a liquid, so that it can be shipped in containers. In this way, LNG could be transported across the Pacific Ocean from U.S. businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it arrives, Vietnam needs technology to turn LNG back into gas so it can be used as fuel. U.S. companies and government agencies are advising on the necessary infrastructure and equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le Van Luc said, “The difficulty and challenge for Vietnam is that we have yet to have any experience in constructing or operating LNG infrastructure.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luc noted that Vietnam is investing in electricity from wind and the sun. But, he said fossil fuels, like natural gas, are still needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le Viet Phuy is an environmental economist with Fulbright University Vietnam. He said the country needs a mixture of ways to produce energy. Le said the country will continue to use coal and increase natural gas while other energy also will be used more. But, he noted that renewable energy is costly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We have seen renewables picking up speed recently, but it will be years until we see some significant impact on the system,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ha Nguyen reported this story for VOANews.com. Mario Ritter Jr. adapted it for Learning English. George Grow was the editor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Image - Liquefied natural gas can be transported by ship and needs infrastructure to be used as a fuel.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Thinh’s Jekyll Blog!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/12/10/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Thinh's Jekyll Blog!" /><published>2018-12-10T10:55:46+07:00</published><updated>2018-12-10T10:55:46+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/12/10/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/12/10/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my demo blog. This blog is using for reporting to my teacher in Environments &amp;amp; Tools For Developing Software subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this demo, I will show my teacher the structures of my blog, some techniques that is used, what did I do to have this output project or answer anything that my teacher require me to explain…and many things else…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have done this demo project, I did refer and consult these following documents, here are those links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll-gh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Welcome to my demo blog. This blog is using for reporting to my teacher in Environments &amp;amp; Tools For Developing Software subject.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cuba Announces Full Internet Access for Mobile Phones</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/06/Cuba-Announces-Full-Internet-Access-for-Mobile-Phones.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cuba Announces Full Internet Access for Mobile Phones" /><published>2018-12-06T15:32:30+07:00</published><updated>2018-12-06T15:32:30+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/06/Cuba%20Announces%20Full%20Internet%20Access%20for%20Mobile%20Phones</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/world/politic/2018/12/06/Cuba-Announces-Full-Internet-Access-for-Mobile-Phones.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/67DBA617-E713-4AA9-A958-D76E476F9932_w1023_r1_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cuba Announces Full Internet Access for Mobile Phones Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image -Cuba’s government announced on Tuesday, Dec. 4, 2018 that its citizens will be offered full internet access on mobile phones starting Thursday, Dec. 6, becoming one of the last nations to do so. (AP Photo/Desmond Boylan, File)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://learningenglish.voanews.com/embed/player/0/4689611.html?type=audio&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;144&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuban officials have announced that the country’s citizens will soon be able to fully use the internet on their mobile phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuba is one of the last nations in the world to offer such service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mayra Arevich is the president of the Cuban state-operated telecommunications company ETECSA. She made the announcement on national television on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said Cubans can begin paying for use of high speed data and voice services that use third generation, or 3G, communication networks on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until now, Cubans have had access only to state-operated email accounts on their phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cuban government has been building a 3G network in cities across the island. Some Cuban government officials and foreign business people and visitors have been able to use the network for several years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communist Party-ruled Cuba has one of the world’s lowest rates of internet use. Internet use increased after former United States President Barack Obama and former Cuban President Raul Castro eased tensions in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That growth has continued at a time when President Donald Trump’s administration has announced economic restrictions on Cuba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/B1582938-E4ED-408A-BEE4-7A994B508582_w650_r0_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cuba Announces Full Internet Access for Mobile Phones Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;    &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image - In this Jan. 6, 2017 photo, people use a public wifi hotspot in Havana, Cuba. Home internet came to Cuba in December 2016, in a limited pilot program&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuba permitted home internet use in 2017. Since that time, hundreds of public wireless internet, or Wi-Fi, connection points have opened in parks and open areas around the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of the new service will be similar to the international average. But it will still be too costly for many Cubans who live on state salaries of about $30 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuba created a high speed internet connection to Venezuela in 2012. This permitted the island to move from slow and costly satellite links. Cuba then began the slow process of permitting citizens to get access to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government started offering internet service at places like cafes in 2013 and Wi-Fi two years later. The number of places offering internet service has grown to more than 800.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cuban internet is mostly uncensored. But the government blocks a small number of sites like the U.S.-supported Radio and TV Marti networks and some others. Radio and TV Marti provide news, information and commentary that Cubans are not likely to receive inside of Cuba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radio and TV Marti is based in Miami, Florida and is operated by the U.S. Agency for Global Media, the same agency that operates VOA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tania Velázquez is vice president of ETECSA. She said the new internet service would become active in stages from Thursday through Saturday. Officials hope to avoid having too many people using the network at one time. Heavy usage caused problems during tests of the mobile network earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Image -Cuba’s government announced on Tuesday, Dec. 4, 2018 that its citizens will be offered full internet access on mobile phones starting Thursday, Dec. 6, becoming one of the last nations to do so. (AP Photo/Desmond Boylan, File)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">‘Mother Mushroom’ to Receive Press Freedom Award</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/vietnam/news/2018/11/15/Mother-Mushroom-to-Receive-Press-Freedom-Award.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="‘Mother Mushroom’ to Receive Press Freedom Award" /><published>2018-11-15T15:32:30+07:00</published><updated>2018-11-15T15:32:30+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/vietnam/news/2018/11/15/%20%E2%80%98Mother%20Mushroom%E2%80%99%20to%20Receive%20Press%20Freedom%20Award</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/vietnam/news/2018/11/15/Mother-Mushroom-to-Receive-Press-Freedom-Award.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/3D5CFA26-666B-4062-A60A-2B4B3013C7E7_cx0_cy10_cw0_w1023_r1_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;‘Mother Mushroom’ to Receive Press Freedom Award Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image -Nguyen Ngoc Nhu Quynh, who goes by the pen name Mother Mushroom, speaks with a reporter during a video conference on her laptop computer in Houston, Texas, October 19, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://learningenglish.voanews.com/embed/player/0/4660438.html?type=audio&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;144&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vietnamese blogger known as “Mother Mushroom” will be honored with an International Press Freedom Award on November 20 in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others who will receive awards are Amal Khalifa Idris Habbani of Sudan, Venezuala’s Luz Mely Reyes, and Anastasiya Stanko of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Committee to Protect Journalists announced the award winners last June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nguyễn Ngọc Như Quỳnh wrote under the name “Mẹ Nấm,” or Mother Mushroom. She was serving a 10-year sentence for “propaganda against the state” when, in 2017, she received an International Women of Courage Award from American first lady Melania Trump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quỳnh was suddenly released from prison in October. She then left Vietnam and went to Houston, in the American state of Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/93F88D57-3321-4038-9EFE-D70FF3A6ED8D_w650_r0_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;‘Mother Mushroom’ to Receive Press Freedom Award Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image - Mẹ Nấm, Mother Mushroom, with her two children in an undated photo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blogger told VOA that it was difficult to accept the offer of her prison release from the Vietnamese government. She said the offer was made on the condition that she leave Vietnam. She thought of her young children whom she had not seen for more than two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quỳnh was reunited with her two children on the flight from Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quỳnh told VOA she began blogging in 2006 while she was pregnant with her daughter. She said, “When I went to a hospital for a check-up, I started to notice that a lot of people around me - who were poor - did not get the same quality of service from medical professionals. And I asked myself, ‘How could I not have seen the unfairness that was happening around me like that?’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On her blog, she wrote about social injustice, environmental issues and the territorial dispute between China and Vietnam over the Spratly Islands. She also helped form the Network of Vietnamese Bloggers, a group of independent journalists who support press freedom in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gdb.voanews.com/0AD35722-7017-4DE8-ABE2-2825CC09E93B_w650_r0_s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;‘Mother Mushroom’ to Receive Press Freedom Award Image&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image - Nguyen Ngoc Nhu Quynh, center, stands trial in the south-central province of Khanh Hoa, Vietnam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quỳnh was first detained in 2009 for writing about the Vietnamese government land confiscation to support a Chinese mining project. She said, “They were afraid that the bilateral government relation could be affected when people like me speak out against the projects.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, Quỳnh did not consider herself to be a member of the press. She said, “I was just exercising my rights to speak for myself, but then they arrested me, and they tried to stop me from blogging, and that was when I realized that I am now an activist for freedom of expression and freedom of the press.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her first few weeks of freedom, Quỳnh has spent time with her two children and her mother. But she plans to start writing again soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said, “I want to continue my blogging and I want to take back my Facebook account [that was blocked in Vietnam] so that I can continue sharing with other people my thoughts and what I aspire to do.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Image -Nguyen Ngoc Nhu Quynh, who goes by the pen name Mother Mushroom, speaks with a reporter during a video conference on her laptop computer in Houston, Texas, October 19, 2018</summary></entry></feed>